[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to pren
tasa Advanced Training as you all know
I've already published 47 YouTube videos
covering beginners level intermediate
level and advanced level Concepts from
past couple of videos onwards have
started teaching you some realtime
scenarios where you might encounter with
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those obstacles while
automating your test cases and this is
our abstra six nothing but lesson six in
terms of real time scenarios and lesson
48 in terms of overall trient tasa
training please do subscribe to the
channel Chanel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos and don't forget to like and
share the video thank you in this lesson
I'm going to teach you how can we solve
for an obstacle where you need to select
the list of items within multi select
list Box by using cality and and
explicit name
Concepts so for that let us first
understand what is the obstacle so this
is our obstacle sixth obstacle testing
methods which is categorized as hard so
let's go for
it so if you see here multi select list
box select all testing methods that are
supported by tasa if you see this is
your multi select box where you can
select all testing methods that are
supported by Taska right so now I can
select
multiple options as well multiple
options as well so now here you need to
select these four options from this
multi- select box so now for that let's
go back to our trient
tasa and
here let's scan objects that are
required to solve the problem okay so
right click on obstacles click on scan
and select
application so this is the application
click on scan
so now let's see here let's expand this
and you can see this is your multi
select but but I don't see the items
within the multi select I don't see
items so for that let us expand the
filter by clicking towards right so here
if you see this is my multi select
select your multi select object you can
see here right
side this is my ID multi select and tag
select and let me select one of the item
I don't want to add all the items
instead I just want to add one item from
the list of items okay let's select the
functional
testing here if you select the
functional testing it says it is not
uniquely identified so don't worry so if
you see right side the properties right
I can see here inner text tag if I
select inner text it's going to uniquely
identify but I don't want to do that
because I would like to use only one
item from the
list and use the same item to select the
rest of the items how by using explicit
name I'm going to explain you okay so
let's just keep only
tag for the one of the item and multi
select I selected ID and tag okay so now
let's go back to your module and rename
this
module with abstrac
name copy
this
and paste this and now save
this and close xcan let's go back to
trient toas so this is the new obstacle
module that we added double click on
this if you see here I can see there is
multi select and functional testing in
instead of functional testing I would
like to name this as item so basically
it's one of the item under multi select
right I'm just naming that as item so
here now let's go to properties click
this right pin okay here so this shows
you the properties of
each element of your or each object if
you see multi select I selected ID and
tag for item I only selected
tag so here because we need to select
multiple
items I have only one object
captured means I can only select one
item so to make sure I can use this item
object multiple
instances you have to look for coordin
if you see here the coordin is showing
as 0 to 1 that means you can use this
attribute
only once in the test
step so now I would like to use this for
how many times I have to use this for
four times 1 2 3 4 right so that's why I
would like to change this
cality from 0 to 1 to 0 to
N I don't want to only restrict for four
times I want to put it as n multiple
times n number of times you can
reuse this object okay that is one thing
and the other thing
is you can use the explicit name concept
here for that for
item right click and add create
configuration
parameter I'll explain you how does this
configuration parameter explicit name
works okay
explicit
name so now you have to make this
explicit name as true why I can start
using the naming convention or index for
this particular item object because I'm
enabling the explicit name feature here
or configuration parameter I'm enabling
here okay so now let's keep it like this
so what we did we have made two changes
one is for item we changed the cordal
from 0 to 1 to 0 to n because I would
like to use the same item selection
multiple times and also we added an
explicit name because I would like to
use this item
to select different
values as an item right one item is
functional testing second is unit
testing third is U GUI testing end to
end testing right so the name of the
value or the name of the item is
different that's why I would like to use
explicit name so that I can select
different values from the multi select
box okay so now let us go to obstacle
and let me create a new test case and
name this with the same obstacle
name double click on this so now I would
like to drag and drop this module to the
test case to create our automation so
basically now let us automate the test
case for that I'm going to drag this
module and drop onto the test
case so now let us expand
this you can see here now you have
multi- select and item okay so here what
I'm going to do here
first I would like
to use the explicit name here if you see
first I would like to select one
functional testing right copy this and
here instead of item I would like to put
functional is
it small testing okay
functional testing see as soon as I
enter some other
value a new item is displaying now that
means a
new attribute has been added let's say
I'll do something here see here see it
is adding one more I'm going to select
this end to end like this okay but
however so let's delete all this okay I
mean let's rename this functional
testing is one value second one is end
to end testing the other
one end to end testing you need to make
sure the exact name match here okay and
then GUI testing
right and then exploratory testing
exploratory testing see as soon as I
enter you will get one more so that
means you can repeat this attribute
multiple times n number of times so here
I am first selecting action mode for
multi select is select that means I'm
just instructing tasar
to consider multi select and then select
the functional testing list item for
that I need to use input and then select
end to endend testing and then select
GUI testing and then select exploratory
testing so
this
coordin is used to
repeat the attribute or this particular
object multiple times and then I'm using
explicit name to rename the attribute so
that it selects item specified here from
the multi list
box okay so now let's chain work state
as completed and save your test case now
let's run the test case and see how it
works right click and run in
scratchbook you solve this automation
problem see here it selected four values
that we entered as an explicit name for
your object so you can see here our test
case is passed so if you have any
queries leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries hope you all understand how can
we solve an obstacle where you need to
select the multiple items from multi
select list Box by using
cardinality and explicit methods by
using tricentis tasa while automating
the test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos and don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]